## Camila Fassarella

(11) 94794-6755 fassarella@me.com

### **Profile**

Multi-tasking immigration specialist with 7+ years of experience with client service and global mobility, as well as national immigration (Brazil). Responsible for delivering tailored immigration services to a diverse portfolio of corporate and private clients.

## Experience

#### SENIOR IMMIGRATION CONSULTANT, NEWLAND CHASE; SÃO PAULO, SP - 2014-2020

- Main point of contact to the client during the whole residency/work authorization and visa process to Brazil and their dependents; process starting with the initial contact to identify the appropriate authorization until their arrival in the country to finalize the immigration process when obtaining the local documents;
- Coordinate with teams in various countries to assist with the process when required (i.e. when documents or authorization from the home country is needed);
- Coordinate with internal team for specific outbound visas (LATAM, US, Schengen, China, etc);
- Training to clients, internal staff and other consultants;
- Elaborate and design standard procedure to optimize the time and to better assist the final client;
- Work closely with managers for constant improvement and better solve issues and government requirements that may arise;
- Responsible for maintaining 100% client excellence.

#### IMMIGRATION SPECIALIST, FRAGOMEN; SÃO PAULO, SP - 2013-2014

 Main point of contact to the client for the whole residency/work authorization and visa process to Brazil and their dependents; process starting with the initial contact to identify the appropriate authorization until their arrival in the country to finalize the immigration process when obtaining the local documents;

#### MARINE VESSELS CONSULTANT, EMDOC; SÃO PAULO, SP - 2011-2012

- Assistance with organization of the Brazilian season cruises and legal needs, such as visas and records;
- Direct contact with the clients, regarding international legal obligations, customer needs and work.

#### INTERNATIONAL & CARGO SECURITY AGENT, AMERICAN AIRLINES; SAO PAULO, SP - 2009-2011

- Responsible to analyze and release travel documents, focusing on security procedures and costumer service according to US (FAA) regulations;
- Analysis and release of documents for cargo export, such as airwaybill, security declarations and invoice, always following US (FAA) regulations as well. Also responsible for physical cargo inspection;
- Outsourced by TriStar

### Education

- Human Resource Management Specialization University of Minnesota 2020
- MasterXPAT Global Mobility Training 2019
- Post-Graduation in Digital Marketing Dom Bosco University 2018-2019
- Bachelor's in International Relations FASM 2003-2006
- International Migrations: a global issue Sciences Po 2018
- Foundations of Everyday Leadership University of Illinois at Urbana-Champaign -2018

# Languages

Portuguese - Native
English - Fluent (C2)
French - Advanced (B2)
Spanish - Working Proficiency (B1)

References available on request